mystarbucksvisit.com 2007-12-29

# Privacy Statement

The Starbucks name and reputation were built on a foundation of trust. This online privacy policy describes the information Starbucks collects through the services available on our web site, Starbucks.com (the “Site”) and the Starbucks Card Program, and how we use that information. Our policy also describes the choices you can make about how we collect and use your information.

StarbucksStore.com is a separate website run by Cooking.com. If you order, make a purchase, or sign up for email communications from Cooking.com via the Starbucksstore.com site, the Cooking.com privacy policy will control how Cooking.com may use your personal information. To view the Cooking.com privacy policy click [here](http://www.starbucksstore.com/products/shourplg.asp).

Starbucks may collect personal information. Personal information means information about an identifiable individual and may include: 

|  | identifying information, such as name, address, e-mail address;  
---|---  
| financial information, such as credit card number; and  
| employment-related information, such as may be found on resumes, applications, background verification information, or in employment references.  

Personal information does not include business contact information (e.g. office address, telephone number) in those jurisdictions that recognize such information as not being personal information.

We may receive personal information from the website of any Starbucks brand, including Tazo® Tea, Hear Music or EthosTM water.   
Personal information will be collected, to the extent possible, directly from the individual concerned. 

In addition to the personal information you actively provide us, we also collect web site use information which includes information about your internet service provider, browser type, domain name, IP address, the web site that referred you to us, the web pages you request, the date and time of those requests, and entry and exit points. Our collection of web site use information may involve the use of cookies and pixel tags. 

Starbucks may also collect aggregated data, which is data from which the identity of an individual cannot be determined. Since it is not personal information, Starbucks may use aggregated data in any way that it considers appropriate. 

Starbucks may use personal information provided verbally or in writing (including via electronic media) by customers and potential employees in order to: 

| Process and manage your purchase of Starbucks products and services, including the purchase and use of your Starbucks Card;  
---|---  
| Communicate with you about your order or purchase, your Starbucks Card account, your Starbucks.com account, or a contest you have entered;   
| Respond to your customer service inquiries;  
| Communicate with you about: |  | specific jobs, job opportunities or general information about employment at Starbucks, in the event you have created a personal profile or submitted your resume online;   
---|---  
| our brands, products, events or other promotional purposes, including co-branded offers, if you have opted to receive such communications either through providing your email address on the home page of Starbucks.com or by indicating as such in your communication preferences when you signed up for a Starbucks.com account;  

| Communicate, to the extent required, with and manage our relationship with Starbucks consultants, strategic partners, agents, distributors, suppliers, contractors and other companies affiliated with Starbucks in order to improve Starbucks offering of products and services; and  
| Meet any applicable legal and regulatory requirement.  

Is my personal information shared with third parties? We may arrange to have marketing and promotional information of other companies sent to you that we think might be of interest to you only if you tell us that you would like to receive these sorts of materials in your communication preferences.

Our website may also share information with companies that provide support services to us (such as credit card processors, mailing houses or web hosts) or that help us market our products and services (such as email vendors). These companies may need information about you in order to perform their functions. These companies are not authorized to use the information we share with them for any other purpose.

We may disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, when required by law, to enforce our corporate policies, or to protect our or others' rights, property, or safety. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes. 

In the event of a sale of some or all of our business, Starbucks may disclose personal information to those involved in a transfer of all or part of the assets or business.

Unless permitted by law, no personal information is collected, without first obtaining your consent for the collection, use and sharing of that information. The provision of personal information to Starbucks means that you agree and consent that we may collect, use and share your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.

In addition, where appropriate, specific authorizations or consents may be obtained from time to time. For example, we may seek consent to use and share personal information after it has been collected in those cases where Starbucks wishes to use the information for a purpose not previously identified or for which the individual concerned has not previously provided consent.

In most cases, and subject to legal and contractual restrictions, an individual is free to refuse or withdraw his or her consent at any time upon reasonable, advance notice. It should be noted that in some circumstances, certain Starbucks products and services can only be offered if a person provides personal information to Starbucks. If you choose not provide us with any required personal information, we may not be able to offer the products or services requested. We will inform you of the consequences of the withdrawal of consent.

We may use your e-mail address and other contact information provided to us through the Site or the Starbucks Card Program to send you promotional materials from us and, if you’ve opted in, from third parties. If you do not want to receive such promotional information, you can change your communication preferences and remove yourself from our e-mail list at any time. If you have a Starbucks.com account, please [log in](https://www.starbucks.com/customer/account.asp) and go to the communication preferences page. If you’ve registered a Starbucks Card over the phone, you may call us at 1-800-STARBUC and we will change your preferences over the phone.

Please also note that even if you opt out of receiving promotional emails from us, we may still use your information to communicate with you for other purposes, such as orders/purchases, your Starbucks Card account, customer service responses and job related communications.

Starbucks strives to ensure that any personal information provided and in its possession is as accurate, current and complete as necessary for the purposes for which we use that information.

If you have signed up for a Starbucks.com account either through registering your Starbucks Card or making a purchase, we have provided you with a means to log into your account and edit your personal information including name, postal address and phone number to ensure its accuracy at all times.

If you signed up to receive email communications by providing your email address on the home page of Starbucks.com, you may either call our customer care line at 1-800-STARBUC to remove your email address or click [here](https://www.starbucks.com/customer/account.asp) to opt out.

If you applied for a position at Starbucks, you can log into the personal profile you created for that purpose and make any necessary changes or updates there.

During your visit to Starbucks.com, we will collect certain web site use information for a number of purposes, namely to: 

Our collection of web site use information may involve the use of cookies. A cookie is a small removable data file that is stored by your web browser on your computer. Cookies allow you to place an order on our website and allow us to enhance and personalize your online surfing and shopping experience. We use cookies to remember the items in your cart, recognize you when you return to our website and analyze visitor behavior.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookie settings. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

We also use pixel tags – tiny graphic images – to help us analyze your online behavior, but we do not tie that behavior to any personal information.

Starbucks strives to maintain appropriate physical, procedural and technical security with respect to its offices and information storage facilities so as to prevent any loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or modification of personal information. This also applies to our disposal or destruction of personal information.

We encrypt the pipe through which personal information, such as credit card numbers, is sent, using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to ensure that your information is safe as it is sent over the Internet to our server. For more information about credit card security, please read our [FAQ](http://www.starbucks.com/customer/faq_qanda.asp?name=card%5Fsecurity).

Starbucks.com is a general audience site that is not designed nor intended to collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Starbucks does not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13, and does not use such information if it discovers that it is has been provided. To respect the privacy of children and to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, children under the age of 13 should not provide any personal information on this Site. We ask that parents supervise their children while online.

Please be aware that we provide links to third-party web sites as a service to our guests, and that we are not responsible for the content or information collection practices of those pages. Please note that these web sites' privacy policies may differ from this privacy policy. We encourage you to review and understand their privacy practices before providing them with information.

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post a new statement on our Site and change the date at the top of the policy. Therefore, we encourage you to check the date of our privacy policy whenever you visit this Site for any updates or changes. If you have provided personal information to us, we will email you any changes to the privacy policy that might affect the way we use your personal information.

We welcome your questions, comments, and concerns about privacy. Please send us any and all feedback pertaining to privacy, or any other issue.

In the event of questions about: (i) access to your personal information; (ii) our collection, use, management or disclosure of personal information; (iii) this privacy policy; or (iv) any other matter, please contact Starbucks Customer Relations. You may also reach Customer Relations by calling (800) 235-2883 or writing to Starbucks Customer Relations, PO Box 3717, Seattle, WA 98124-3717. Starbucks will investigate all complaints and if a complaint is justified, we will take all reasonable steps to resolve the issue.

Please also visit our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.starbucks.com/customer/legal.asp) section that explains other terms governing the use of this Site.
